CHINTAMANI SADANAND CHAVAN

@ chintamani.chavan08@gmail.com

(585) 386-9947

Rochester, NY

in /chintamanichavan

? /chintamanichavan

PROFILE

Inquisitive computer science student and a quick learner who possesses broad technical knowledge. Experienced in developing DevOps, computing strategies. Keeps informed of the latest trends in technology.

- Python Azure GCP Networking Linux Algorithms and Data Structures JavaScript Ansible
- Terraform Bash Docker Kubernetes MySQL
- MongoDB Git PowerShell NSIS

EDUCATION

Master's in Networking & Systems Administration

Rochester Institute of Technology

Expected Graduation: Dec 2020

≈ 3.87 GPA

Bachelor's in Computer Science & Engineering

University of Mumbai

Graduation: July 2017

3.9 GPA

PROJECTS & ACTIVITIES

Auto-Deployment pipeline for a Web Application using Google Kubernetes Engine(GKE)

- Developed a Expense tracker application with the use of Python framework Django.
- Packaged the application on a container instance to create an application build using GKE.
- Used GKE to implement auto-scaling, auto-repair of failing nodes and auto-upgrade to latest stable version of application.
- Used Cloud Build to setup auto deployment pipeline for GKE application workload.
- GitHub Repo: https://github.com/chintamanichavan/ Expense-and-Portfolio-Tracker

Sign Language Detection using ACTION RECOGNITION

- Collected KeyPoints from MediaPipe Holisitc.
- Trained a deep neural network with Long Short-Term (LSTM) layers for sequences.
- Performed real-time sign language detection using OpenCV library.

Al Smile Detector

- Used Haar Algorithm to detect the Face and Smile within the face from the live Webcam feed .
- Used OpenCV library to implement the real-time computer vision.
- GitHub Repo: https://github.com/chintamanichavan/Real-Time-Face-and-Smile-Detection

EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer

Cardinal Capital LLC

🛗 Apr 2021 - Current

Chicago, IL

- Created Dashboards for trade monitoring and reporting
- Set up Airflow Clusters to monitor and orchestrate trade scripts execution.
- Set up DB and Trade Servers for e-trading.
- Set up data and CI/CD piplelines on AWS to create seamless development workflow for developers.

Systems Engineer I

Modis

May 2021 - March 2022

Rochester, NY

- Working for Modis client Fujifilm as a Systems Engineer on a Kiosk-based Web Application Project.
- Working with scripting languages like Python, Powershell, Bash and NSIS to automate the application workflows.
- Working with Azure DevOps Server to set up the CI/CD workflows to generate automated application builds.
- Designed and Configured the Docker containers to implement the portable deployment of the application.
- Developed a build script that can reduce the downtime on the servers from 15 minutes to 30 seconds between the new release installations.

Graduate Assistant

Rochester Institute of Technology

August 2019 - May 2020

♀ Rochester, NY

- Handle Imaging for lab environments, perform thorough troubleshooting, and apply an immediate fix for incident/issue resolution.
- Developed a Powershell script to automatically update licenses for 120+ computers with a 98% success rate that saved 8 hours of work per computer.
- Systems management and assists in problem determination, working towards maintaining 99.99% of up time.

LEADERSHIP & AWARDS

- Supervised 28 Lab Assistants while working at IST lab at Rochester Institute of Technology as Assistant System Administrator
- 100% Merit Scholarship, RIT
- Aaryabhatta Award, University of Mumbai